[
    {
        "id": "01",
        "question" : "MIDI was developed in ___ year.",
        "options": [
            "1982",
            "1956",
            "1995",
            "1958"
        ],
        "answer": "1982"
    },
    {
        "id": "02",
        "question" : "Whats is multimedia file?",
        "options": [
            "is same as any other regular file",
            "must be accessed at specific rate",
            "stored on remote server can not be delivered to its client",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "must be accessed at specific rate"
    },
    {
        "id": "03",
        "question" : "In which type of streaming multimedia file is delivered to the client, but not shared?",
        "options": [
            "real-time streaming",
            "progressive download",
            "compression",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "answer": "real-time streaming"
    },
    {
        "id": "04",
        "question" : "Which one of the following is the characteristic of a multimedia system?",
        "options": [
            "high storage",
            "high data rates",
            "both high storage and high data rates",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "both high storage and high data rates"
    },
    {
        "id": "05",
        "question" : "In teardown state of real time streaming protocol is ___________",
        "options": [
            "the server resources for client",
            "server delivers the stream to client",
            "server suspends delivery of stream",
            "server breaks down the connection"
        ],
        "answer": "server breaks down the connection"
    },
    {
        "id": "06",
        "question" : "Multimedia system require hard real time scheduling ___________",
        "options": [
            "to ensure critical tasks will be serviced within timing deadlines",
            "to deliver the media file to the client",
            "to minimize the delay",
            "for security"
        ],
        "answer": "to ensure critical tasks will be serviced within timing deadlines"
    },
    {
        "id": "07",
        "question" : "A smaller version of an image is called a:",
        "options": [
            "Clipart",
            "Bitmap",
            "Portable Network Graphic",
            "Thumbnail"
        ],
        "answer": "Thumbnail"
    },
    {
        "id": "08",
        "question" : "______________ is the special effect used to introduce each slide in a slide presentation.",
        "options": [
            "Animation",
            "Bulleting",
            "Transition",
            "Mapping"
        ],
        "answer": "Transition"
    },
    {
        "id": "09",
        "question" : "A video consists of a sequence of",
        "options": [
            "Frames",
            "Signals",
            "Packets",
            "Slots"
        ],
        "answer": "Frames"
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "question" : "Moving Picture Experts Group (MPEG) is used to compress",
        "options": [
            "Frames",
            "Images",
            "Audio",
            "Video"
        ],
        "answer": "Video"
    },
    {
        "id": "11",
        "question" : "One of the disadvantages of multimedia is",
        "options": [
            "cost",
            "adaptability",
            "usability",
            "relativity"
        ],
        "answer": "cost"
    }
,{
    "id": "12",
    "question" : "Multimedia is also used for ___ communications and presentations",
    "options": [
        "Corporate",
        "Company",
        "Communal",
        "Commercial"
    ],
    "answer": "Corporate"
}

,{
    "id": "13",
    "question" : "Multimedia is widely used to add special ____ to moviesr",
    "options": [
        "arrangement",
        "attachments",
        "control",
        "effects"
    ],
    "answer": "effects"
}

,{
    "id": "14",
    "question" : "The ___ input addresses the different styles of different users",
    "options": [
        "Multi-sense",
        "Multimedia",
        "Multi-facet",
        "Multi-sensory"
    ],
    "answer": "Multi-sensory"
}
,{
    "id": "15",
    "question" : "The shockwave format was developed by",
    "options": [
        "IBM",
        "Apple",
        "Macromedia",
        "Microsoft"
    ],
    "answer": "Macromedia"
}



   

]